forces.net 2018-12-12

# Privacy Policy

1\. This privacy policy sets out the basis on which we will process any personal data that we collect from you or that you provide to us when you use our website or any of the services provided through it or when you enter any competitions that we are responsible for. Please read the following privacy policy carefully to understand how we use and protect the information that you provide to us. When you enter a competition, or use our website or any of the services offered through it you are consenting to our processing of your personal data in accordance with this privacy policy. This policy is effective from 25th May 2018. 

##  **Contacting Us**

2\. For the purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation and the Data Protection Act 2018, The Services Sound and Vision Corporation ("We", "Us" "Our") will be the data controller in respect of any personal data that you submit to us or that we collect from you when using our website or when you enter one of our competitions irrespective of the method that you choose to submit your entry. We are a private company limited by guarantee and a UK registered charity. Our registered charity number is 233480 and our company registration number is 407270. Our registered office is at Chalfont Grove, Narcot Lane, Chalfont St Peter, Buckinghamshire, SL9 8TN. For more information about us please visit the [about us](http://www.ssvc.com/) page on our website. 

3\. If you would like to know what information we hold about you or if you have any other queries or complaints in relation to this privacy policy, or our website, our contact details are as follows: 

Complete the Forces.net Information access request form [HERE ](https://app-eu.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/443fe866-adbf-46b4-86ff-a8cf91713987)

Or you can write to us as well: 

The Services Sound and Vision Corporation   
Chalfont Grove   
Narcot Lane   
Chalfont St Peter   
Buckinghamshire   
SL9 8TN 

Or you can email us as well:   
Email: [GDPR@ssvc.com](mailto:GDPR@ssvc.com) 

##  **The information that we collect from you**

4\. We will collect the information that you provide to us when you submit an entry into any competitions that we are running either on our website or via any of our broadcast services including our radio or television channels or through any social media websites that we use to announce our competitions such as Facebook or Twitter. This information may vary depending on the type of competition but will often include your name, age, gender, home address, email address and telephone number. We will use this information to administer the competition you have entered including to contact you if you have won a prize. We may also need to share this information with any third parties who are providing any prizes or other products and services as part of the competition, but we will not share this information with third parties for marketing purposes. 

5\.  We will collect any information contained in any correspondence between you and us. For example, if you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence. We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with our website or any content or services made available through it. 

6\.  We do not collect, store or use any personal information contained in any messages posted on our website. Please note that any materials or information that you post to our website may be visible to other users of the site. We advise you to be selective about what information you post on the website. For more information please visit [www.gov.uk/think-before-you-share](http://www.gov.uk/think-before-you-share). 

7\.  We may collect certain information about your visits to our website and how you use it. This may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and number of page views and similar information. We may use this information for a number of purposes including website administration, optimising the use and performance of the website, disclosing to third party contributors or for security purposes. Individual users will not be identifiable from this information. This information may be collected by a third-party website analytics service provider on our behalf and may be collected using cookies. For more information on our use of cookies please refer to the cookie section below. 

8\.  In some instances, we may receive some information that you submit to any third-party website that you access from a link contained in our website. Both us and the owner or operator of that third-party website will be the data controller in respect of any such information. You should check the privacy policy of that website to find out how they will use your data. 

##  **Use of your information**

9\.  We will only use the personal information that we collect from you in accordance with this privacy policy. We may use your information for the following purposes:

a) to ensure that content from the website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;

b) to send you general (non-marketing) commercial communications, such as information about the website and services provided to you by us at that time;

c) to provide customer service in relation to your use of the website, to contact you, to deal with enquiries and complaints relating to the use of the website

d) to develop, improve and personalise the website so as to improve your user browsing experience; and

e) to provide third parties with statistical information about our users but this information will not be able to be used to identify any individual user.

##  **Schedule of Privacy Notices  **

10\. SSVC collect data across the business for different purposes.  Please click on the link HERE to view the schedule of privacy notices that could apply. 

##  **Our complaints procedure  **

11\. SSVC make every effort to comply with the requirements for the timely delivery of privacy information requests. We will also respond to complaints about our process as fast as possible.  

12\. Data subjects can complain to SSVC about: 

a) how their personal data has been processed 

b) how their request for access to data has been handled 

c) how their complaint has been handled  

d) appeal against any decision made following a complaint 

13\. Data subject(s) lodging a complaint with the Data Protection Officer (currently Finance Manager) can do so via email at [gdpr@ssvc.com.  ](mailto:gdpr@ssvc.com.%20)

Complaints received are directed to the Data Protection Officer (currently Finance Manager) for resolution.   We aim to resolve complaints within 4 weeks.  Appeals on the handling of complaints are to be resolved within 3 months. 

14\. The data subject may also write into the organisation:    

The Privacy Officer    
SSVC    
Chalfont Grove, Narcot Lane, Gerrard’s Cross, Buckinghamshire, SL9 8TN  

##  **Disclosure of your information**

15\. Other than as expressly set out in this privacy policy or as otherwise required or permitted by law, we will not share, sell or distribute any of the information you provide to us without your consent.

16.  We may disclose your personal information to:

a) any third party to whom disclosure is necessary to enable us to provide you with any services or products that you have requested through the site including any of our competition prizes which may be provided by such third parties; and/or

b) any person to whom disclosure is necessary to enable us to enforce our legal rights, or to protect the rights, property or safety of The Services Sound and Vision Corporation or our members or employees or the safety or security of any member of the UK’s armed forces or their family or supporters or where such disclosure may be required by law.

17\.  You should note that the public elements of the website, such as the Forces Radio BFBS message board, will be visible to other users of the website anywhere in the world. You should therefore be careful when submitting information about yourself and only submit information that you are happy to be public information.

##  **Cookies**

18\.  In common with other websites we use cookies to ensure that you get the most out of our website and to improve the service we offer. A cookie is a text file containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your device when you access a website. The text file is then sent back to the server each time your browser requests a page from the server. This enables the web server to identify and track the web browser you are using. 

19\.  Some cookies that we use are necessary for our websites to function properly and to enable you to move around the site and use its features. In addition, we also use so called "functional" cookies that allow our websites to remember choices you have made in relation to the websites to provide a more personalised and enhanced user experience. 

20\.  As mentioned above, we may also use an analytics service provider, such as Google Analytics, for website traffic analysis and reporting. Analytics service providers generate statistical and other information about websites use by means of cookies, which are stored on users' computers. The information generated relating to the websites may be used to create reports about the use of the websites and the analytics service provider will store this information.

21\.  If you do not wish us to install cookies on your computer for these purposes, you may change the settings on your internet browser to reject cookies. For more information please consult the "Help" section of your browser. Please note that if you do set your browser to reject cookies, you may not be able to use all of the features of our websites. To indicate your acceptance of our use of cookies in accordance with this privacy policy you can click accept in the appropriate place on the banner that appears on our site. However, please note that if you do not click accept but you continue to browse our websites you will be deemed to have accepted our use of cookies in accordance with this privacy policy.

##  **Third party content, websites and contributors**

22\.  Our websites may contain content and links to other websites and microsites that are operated by third parties. In addition, advertisements contained on our websites may operate as links to that advertiser’s websites, and such advertisers and third parties may also use and place cookies on your computer.

23\.  We do not control and accept no liability or responsibility for these third party websites, advertisements and cookies. This privacy policy does not apply to such third party websites, microsites, advertisements and cookies and any information such third parties collect by virtue of you clicking one third party link on our websites will be collected and used in accordance with the privacy policy of that third party. Please therefore consult the terms and conditions and privacy policy of those third party websites and microsites to find out how they collect and use your personal data and to establish whether and for what purpose they use cookies.

##  **Security and data retention**

24\.  We employ appropriate technological and operational security measures to protect against any unauthorised access to or any unlawful processing of any personal information about you that we hold. We will retain your information for a reasonable period or as long as the law requires or permits.

25\.  Data transmission over the internet is inherently insecure, and although we employ appropriate technological and organisational security measures to protect your data we cannot guarantee the security of any data sent over the internet.

##  **International data transfers**

26\.  Our servers are situated in the UK, however we collect data from wherever users are situated. The information that we collect will therefore be transferred to the UK from any other country in which you may be located and will be subject to UK data protection laws rather than the laws of the country in which you are resident.

27\.  We do not transfer personal data collected via our websites or through any competitions we run outside the European Economic Area (unless you have consented; it is necessary to provide the services you have requested; or it is otherwise required or permitted by law).

##  **Your rights**

28\. Under the Data Protection Act 2018, you have the following rights that we need to make you aware of. You are not required to pay any charge for exercising your rights. However, we will charge a ‘reasonable fee’ when a request is manifestly unfounded or excessive, particularly if it is repetitive. This also applies to additional copies of the same information. You can exercise you rights by contacting us using the contact information provided in section 1 above. We have one month to respond to you. This period can be extended by a further two months where requests are complex or numerous. If this is the case, we will inform you within one month of the receipt of the request and explain why the extension is necessary.

a) Your right to be informed: this right is fulfilled through this privacy policy.

b) Your right of access: You have the right to ask us for copies of your personal information (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you.

c) Your right to rectification: You have the right to ask us to rectify any information we hold about you that you think is inaccurate or incomplete.

d) Your right to erasure: You have the right to ask us to erase your personal information. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it.

e) Your right to restrict processing: You have the right to ask us to restrict the processing of your information. When processing is restricted, we are permitted to store the personal data, but not further process it.

f) Your right to object to processing: You have the right to object to processing your personal data if the processing is based on legitimate interests (including profiling) or where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes.

g) Your right to data portability: You have the right to ask us to transfer the information you gave us to another organisation, or to give it to you. The right only applies if we are processing information based on your consent or in talks about entering into a contract and the processing is automated.

##  **Changes to our privacy policy**

29\.  We reserve the right to make changes to this privacy policy from time to time. Any such changes to our privacy policy will be posted to our websites.
